#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/chekotirakesh-38a582102 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Recruiting
Infrastructure
Hiring

Honors-Awards

Best Performance

# Chekoti Rakesh

Account Manager-(HCL Tech)

Frisco, Texas, United States

## Summary

Experienced Senior Talent Acquisition Specialist with a demonstrated history of working in the staffing and recruiting industry. Skilled in Negotiation, Screening, Recruiting, Profiles, and Infrastructure. Strong human resources professional graduated from holy Mary business school.

## Experience

W3Global

Account Manager-(HCL Tech)
February 2023 - Present (1 year 11 months)
Frisco, TX

,

#### SAGE IT

Team Lead (HCL Tech) September 2022 - February 2023 (6 months)

Frisco, Texas, United States

Yochana IT Solutions INC
Senior Talent Acquisition (HCL Tech)
April 2016 - September 2022 (6 years 6 months)
23000 Commerce Drive, Farmington Hills, MI 48335, USA

- Identify candidates as per the IT job requirements by studying job description and job qualifications
- Conduct initial screenings, reference checks, negotiate pay rate, relocation, coordinate Client interviews and work with the Account Managers to close the requirement
- Built and maintained strong relationships, having a keen sense of negotiation with Candidates and employers.
- Nurtured strong working relationships with staffing community and other team members to create a partnership that yields success, predictable results, and credibility.
- Working with Account Managers and Recruitment team on a wide variety of Infrastructure Requirements.

- Maintaining good submittal to Interview/Placement ratio
- Extensively worked on Various Skills including (Supporting Roles/Network Engineer OR Architect/ Program Manager/ Cloud Architect/ GCP/AWS/ Azure )Requirements
- Sourcing from Job Portals (Career Builder, Monster, Dice, LinkedIn)
- Use sourcing channels -, LinkedIn, Mass email etc.
- Experience with ATS tools like (Cepal,Orrwin)
- Assisting with the onboarding of new volunteers.
- MIS Report and Maintaining Database on Daily basis
- Trained and lead a team 5 recruiters spread across the globe
- Kept track of my team's work and responsible for maintaining various activity trackers, Daily Status Reports and Weekly Status Reports
- Supports completion and collection of pre-hire paperwork/On-boarding Paperwork like-signed offer letters, BGV (Back Ground Verification),MSA&PO,CBSV,I9.
- Answering client calls and submitting profiles to the clients in the absence of manager.
- Training fresher's and helping team members.
- Attending client meeting and calls regular basis to understand the requirements and assist the client on various aspects.

### Education

holy Mary business school

Master's degree, Marketing/Marketing Management, General · (2014 - 2016)